hey everyone my name is Amber effin and
I'm gonna talk to you today about the
Angel of the battlefield Clara Barton
okay
our story begins during the Civil War
it's got in fatalities when people are
okay so the Union Army is surgeon dr.
James Dunne was like hey dudes this is
some
we are low on antiseptic we are low on
vintages we do not have the supplies to
handle DML bloodshed okay
meanwhile a teacher Clara Barton is like
I want to worry about the soldiers of
the Union Army hello government we need
more medical supplies can you help me
help you're in soldiers and the
government is like
no and she's like you know what your
bitch-ass this have come correct they're
like we will not come cool come Griffin
oh I'm sorry I'm yelling oh my gosh I'm
also sorry for being sorry cuz who does
that help
no one ah okay so she asks the Ladies
Aid Society
send me medical supplies and I will
bring them to the front lines
meanwhile in Sharpsburg Maryland the
Confederate General Robert Ely was like
it is September 17th 1862 and that's
when the Battle of Antietam begin the
Battle of Antietam was the bloodiest
single-day battle in American history
so Jamestown is like we are grossly
under prepared and it's at that exact
moment that it bursts Clara Barton with
a train of wagons filled with supplies
and she's like watch out everybody does
a union is coming that's a good yeah
yeah you also everybody I brought us
everything you need dr. James Dunn is
like I need antiseptic she's like I got
that he's like do you have bandages
she's like yeah I got bandages
he's like what we need is normal
like socks and food and she's like you
know what
[Music]
abracadabra and he's like oh my
god you are
Angel of the battlefield thank you
thinking thinking thinking thank you
she's like stop thanking me I have work
to do
she starts working on wounded soldiers
with no experience whatsoever and at
that moment a bullet Pierce's her sleeve
and she's like see this and the guy
is like I don't see that cuz I'm
dead
cuz the bullet that pierced her sleeve
killed the very guy she was saving so
she's like this sucks but I am going to
move on to the next thing then we went
to the next thing she knows and at the
end of the day dr. James Dunne is
sitting by himself
any dark burn Clara Barton is like
doctor done with him I'm redoing he's
like I am depressed night has fallen I
can't see hundreds of soldiers will
die but her Barton is like don't
you know she grabs him by the hand she
takes him to another bird
and this burner is lit with lanterns
she's like you think of what your way
sucks but I didn't bring you lantern
something light your surgeries is wrong
with you and he's like I love you so
much you are truly the angel of benefit
Clara Barton is like you don't call me
that already come up with some new
she doesn't burp but I wish she did so
that I could also work she was like
amber if you feel like burping Kimber
and I am like I'm darker than anything
she's like you're very drugged and I'm
like okay so that's the end of the war
and everyone is like Clara Barton you
and someone special wants to meet with
you President Abraham Lincoln and
President Lincoln is like Clara Barton
you did such a good job at the Battle of
Antietam you need to be the head of the
US office offices the aasif the office
who IAM is drunk but when he means this
Reverend you need to be the head of the
office of missing soldiers she's like I
will a super will answer she finds over
22,000 soldiers President Lincoln is
like on fire and then they kiss
just kidding they never gets and in 1878
Clara Barton started the American
chapter of the Red Cross Clara Barton is
like I am the founder of the American
Red Cross plus I'm the Angel of the
battlefield you changed America itself I
win and everyone is like do it
yeah
[Music]
you